Luis Herrera

Cali, Valle del Cauca, Colombia



linkedin.com/in/lh1008



1209@holbertonschool.com



3057128788

Summary

Cryptocurrency privacy-focused Monero (XMR) enthusiast. Focused in open-source software GNU/Linux operating systems since 2016.

Studied Software Engineering foundations at Holberton School Colombia with a high passion for blockchain technology. Entrepreneur, adventurer, and eager to develop code for our world.

Experience in C, Python, and JavaScript programming languages, hand-coded HTML and CSS with MySQL database integration.

Experience



Communication Work-group Coordinator (Volunteer)

Monero

Jul 2018 - Present (2 years 2 months +)

Workgroup production coordinator. Organize translators, transcriptionist's workload and publish final content throughout the community.



🔙 Software Engineer

Rappi

May 2020 - Jun 2020 (2 months)

This project proposes a workforce based credit system, implementing technology and performance. The main goal is to facilitate fast loan access to workers based on their performance. We have two main participants. Investors and workers. Investors invest in the loan system based on the worker's score and workers will have access to the loan depending on their performance.

Software Engineer

Holberton School

Sep 2019 - Jun 2020 (10 months)

Full-time programmer. Experience with C, Python, and Javascript programming languages, MySQL (SQLalchemy) database management, HTML, and CSS web frameworks.

During this project, we developed 3 low-level C programming & algorithms projects, 4 higher level Python and JavaScript programming projects, 8 system engineering DevOps projects, a Social Media profile, and our own portfolio project that was live transmitted through Facebook live. We also used MySQL as relational database management systems, SQLalchemy, RESTful, and JavaScript APIs and deployed virtual servers using Docker and hardware servers.

■ Database Analyst

EMCALI - Telecomunicaciones

Sep 2016 - Feb 2018 (1 year 6 months)

Database analyst. I also did the Geographic Information System software (GEOVISOR/MapInfo) colleagues training. My main task was to maintain the database information updated using the integrated OPEN-

SmartFlex software. Databases were handled using Microsoft Excel crossed-based between different government official databases (FOSYGA, RUAF, DIAN, and PROCURADURIA).

Business Development Administrator

Productos Vrinda

Feb 2013 - May 2016 (3 years 4 months)

Production and service manager. My responsibilities were to cover the customer service area, staff planning, purchase, storage, and sales. I had to contact suppliers, make the financial accounting control, have resource optimization, and comply with quality standards and regulations of the food and beverage sector.

Georeferencer

Servinformación

Feb 2010 - Feb 2013 (3 years 1 month)

Homologate national property number in the company's databases to the EMCALI subscriber. I also made routing fieldwork through Geographic Information Systems (GIS). Geographic software layer control, collector supervisor, and location coordinates updates. Software: MapInfo, Excel, Access.

Report Commercial Director

Chef en tu Casa

2012 - 2012 (1 year)

Logistics, purchases, accounting, and cash management.

■ CSR

Kimeline

Dec 2010 - Mar 2011 (4 months)

Customer Service Representative

Education

Holberton School

Software Engineer, Programming

2019 - 2021

Udemy Academy

Web Designer, Web Development

2017 - 2018

Design, update, and web structure development using HTML and CSS. SEO positioning, CSS and 3D animations. Domain hosting and account management.

Economics, Economy

The economics career analyzes the individual and his social-economic behavior. The implementation of econometric analysis is essential for understanding social organization.

Licenses & Certifications

EF SET English Certificate 94/100 (C1 Advanced) - EF Standard English Test (EF SET)

Skills

Open Source Software • Programming • Software Development • MySQL • Microsoft Office • JavaScript • English • C (Programming Language) • Python (Programming Language)